Easy Riders, Raging Bulls: How the Sex 'n' Drugs 'n' Rock 'n' Roll Generation Saved
Hollywood is a documentary, history film directed by Kenneth Bowser.
The chronicle of the mind-blowing journey that was Hollywood during the seventies; the true and gripping story of the last golden age of American cinema, an exalted celebration
of creativity and experimentation; but also of sex, drugs and rock 'n' roll: a turbulent and dark tale of ambition, envy, betrayal, hatred and self-destruction.
Self - Narrator (voice), played by William H. Macy.
Self, played by Dede Allen.
Self, played by Peter Bart.
Self, played by Tony Bill.
Self, played by Karen Black.
Self, played by Peter Bogdanovich.
Easy Riders, Raging Bulls: How the Sex-Drugs-and-Rock 'N Roll Generation Saved Hollywood is a book by Peter Biskind, published by Simon & Schuster in 1998, about ostensibly 1960s and 1970s Hollywood, a period of
American film known for the production of such films such as The Godfather, The Godfather Part II, The French Connection, Chinatown, Taxi Driver, Jaws, Star Wars, The Exorcist, and The Last Picture Show.
The book presents a comprehensive look into the people who influenced these
pictures and who continue to influence modern day filmmaking.
The title is taken from films which bookend the era:
Easy Rider (1969) and Raging Bull (1980).
The book was the basis of a 2003 documentary film of the same title,
directed by Kenneth Bowser and narrated by actor William H.
The documentary was screened out of competition
at the 2003 Cannes Film Festival.
Rotten Tomatoes gives the film a score of 100%,
aggregated from the input of eight contributors.
The film explores themes of cinema on cinema, movie
business, 1970s, hollywood, 1980s.
The tone is dark and intense.